Register of the Mikhail S. Bernstam miscellaneous papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Mikhail S. Bernstam miscellaneous papers
1975-2004
94065
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, printed matter, memorabilia, and photographs relating to political and economic conditions in Russia. Includes letters by Aleksandr Solzhenit͡syn.
Bernstam, Mikhail S.
Solzhenit͡syn, Aleksandr Isaevich, 1918-2008.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1994.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Russian-American economist; Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution at Stanford University.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, printed matter, memorabilia, and photographs relating to political and economic conditions in Russia. Includes letters by Aleksandr Solzhenit͡syn.
Russia (Federation)--Politics and government--1991-; Russia (Federation)--Economic conditions--1991-
- Correspondence, 1981-2004
  - Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, 1981-1992
    - 1981 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - 1987-1992 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Natalia Solzhenitsyn, 1988-2004 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    Scope and Contents note
    Letters to Bernstam and his family.
  - General, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Printed Matter, 1992-1993
  - Economic reform programs of the Russian government (two volumes)
    - 1992 June (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1992 October (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - "Russia and the Commonwealth in a Race Between Democracy and Dictatorship, September-October 1993" by Mikhail S. Bernstam (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Issuances of the Russian Parliament, 1993 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Photographs, 1975-1990 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  Photographs depicting Bernstam family members with Aleksandr Solzhenit͡syn, and one photograph of Bernstam with Russian president Boris Yeltsin at a meeting with Hoover Institution fellows.
- Memorabilia, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  A commemorative pocket watch issued in limited edition in 1990. The watch symbolizes the step-by-step program of market reform in Russia called "500 Days." In January 1991, Russian leading politicians contacted Bernstam and asked him to assemble a group of American economists who would offer a new program. In March 1991, Hoover Institution fellows flew to Moscow and met with Mr. Yeltsin. As a token of appreciation, the office of Mr. Yeltsin presented Bernstam with the commemorative pocket watch "500 Days."